Conor Burns Curriculum Vitae

Personal Profile

An ambitious, enthusiastic, and technically focused Software Developer with a breadth of knowledge primarily in Java as well as PHP, HTML, CSS, Linux, and Python. Recently has gained excellent experience in IT/Network Security and received the Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer certificate. Completed a Master's in Software Development at Queens University and a MA Hons in Business and Finance at Heriot Watt University. A fast learner, creative with an aptitude for problem solving. An exemplary track record of organization, time management and meticulous attention to detail.

Spirit AeroSystems Dec 2021 – June 2022

Joined Spirit AeroSystems to assist both their IT and Network teams during an overhaul of company cyber-security and network infrastructure after an acquisition.

- Working in a team, built, repaired, replaced, and monitored around 3000 active legacy/modern machines between 5 different workplace sites (factory and office).
- Operated as an admin to fix user related incidents as well as service requests through the asset management software and ticketing system Maximo.
- Established and maintained digital communication software, including email, user logins and passwords. This included setting up new employees and troubleshooting existing ones.
- Part of the software review team assessing viable replacements or additions for factory operations and conducting research on network products/services.
- Part of the software packaging team testing new software to be deployed on Spirits domain joined systems.
- Oversaw installation, configuration, maintenance, and troubleshooting of network connected end-user hardware, software, and peripheral devices.
- Installed, configured, and maintained network cabling and other networking equipment such as hubs, switches, and UPS.
- Worked in close cooperation with Systems Analyst and Lead Information Technology Technician to facilitate management of computer systems.
- Documentation and utilisation of data and password retrieval processes.
- System and Network Migration upgrading to windows 7/10 and movement towards updated cloud-based networking which involved network design and capacity planning.
- Open line with Dell repair team to organise part delivery, repair requests and troubleshooting.

Professional Employment

Developed a range of skills, work ethic and discipline whilst working part time in the hospitality sector. Data Analyst / IT, Spirit AeroSystems **Dec 2021 – June 2022** Christmas 2019, Bar Staff / Waiter, Belvoir Park Golf Club - Belfast Jun 2019 - Sep 2019 Bar staff / Waiter, Rota - Edinburgh Aug 2018 - Apr 2019 Shop Assistant / Delivery Assistant, CS Suppliers - Belfast Jun 2018- Sep 2018 Pianist, Dobbie's Restaurant - Belfast Jul 2017 - Aug 2017, December 2017 Bar Staff / Waiter, Club Espionage - Edinburgh Jun 2017- Jul 2017 Bar Staff / Waiter, The Three Sisters - Edinburgh Feb 2016- Jun 2017 Bar Staff / Waiter, Albany Bar and Restaurant - Belfast Jul 2016- Aug 2016, Christmas 2016 Kitchen Porter / Waiter, Belvoir Park Golf Club - Belfast Jun 2016- Jul 2016 Drama Instructor / Teacher, Drama Works - Belfast 2015 - 2016

Education

Queens university Belfast: 2020 - 2021 MSC Software Development

Notable Modules:

- Databases (SQL)
- Software Engineering
- Programming (Java)
- Web Development (HTML)
- Computing Foundations
- Principles and Practices of Machine Learning (Python)
- User Experience Design
- Security Networks

Heriot Watt University: 2015 - 2020 MA (Hons) Business and Finance: 2.1

Notable Modules:

- Risk Management and Derivatives
- Equity Markets and Fund Management
- Mergers and Acquisitions
- International Bond and Currency Markets
- Agency Theory and Corporate Governance

Methodist College Belfast: 2008 - 2015

A Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (C), Geography (C)

Interests, Skills, and Achievements

Sport – My most regular sports would be golf, tennis, table tennis and squash. Throughout my time at university I played pool for the Heriot Watt 2nd team and won the Scottish University Pool Association Team Trophy at the Scottish University SUPA event.

Music - I took Grade 8 Level a number of years ago and have gone onto develop my skills and style playing a range of musical genres. I have awards in both Grade 5 music theory and Grade 5 Piano.

Other - In my final year I was also President of the Heriot Watt Poker Society which required me to set up and manage weekly events for around 100 members. I love to play chess and have reached a 1900 unofficial Elo rating.

Computing/ICT- I possess good working knowledge and experience using Microsoft apps and services such as Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneDrive, Outlook, and Microsoft Teams.

Additional Qualifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer - Java SE Programmer I exam (1Z0-808)

Duke of Edinburgh - Bronze & Silver Awards

Speech and Drama - Merit in Grade 7 Silver Medal

Piano - Awards in both Grade 5 music theory and Grade 5 Piano.

Academic Experience:

Databases:

Creating and operating a MYSQL database, use of PHP commands and SQL functions, Data Security and Encryption. ER Notation, Normalization, Foreign Keys, Sub Queries, Joins and Transactions.

Programming (Java):

Basic principles of programming, Principles of object-oriented design (objects, classes, methods, interfaces, abstraction, inheritance, encapsulation, and polymorphism) and advanced principals (exception handling, threading, data collection).

Software Engineering:

Developed an understanding of the process to take a significant software development project from requirements analysis through to software delivery. Worked as a team to design a text game in Java. Project Scheduling, Requirements Engineering, Domain Models, UML Diagrams and Testing Strategies.

Web Development:

Client-side web technologies: HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Server-side technologies: PHP with MySQL. Data-driven web-based development building an interactive and dynamic web-based system. Constructed a website that rated movies on Netflix. Allowed account creation, database queries, modifications and implemented security precautions. Used Postman as an API platform and for testing.

Computing Foundations:

Computer design and architecture, information processing, data storage and manipulation, algorithms, and algorithmic solution of problems (sorting/searching), networking and security, software development and testing. Practice using Linux learning all basic commands.

Principles and Practices of Machine Learning:

Methods including Clustering, Classification, Neural Networks, Principal Component Analysis (PCA) and Non-Negative Matrix Factorization (NMF). Built using R programming for statistical computing and Pytorch as the machine learning framework. Use of Anaconda, Linux and Python3 on Jupyter Notebook.

User Experience Design:

Worked in a team of 5 to design a User Interface for a smart mirror. Developed understanding on how to present information on a screen efficiently and aesthetically.

Secure Software Networks:

Set up a virtual machine through the Linux distribution ubuntu to replicate cyber-attacks and security precautions using tools such as Mininet, Wireshark, Snort, Nmap and FileZilla.

Java SE Programmer I exam (1Z0-808):

Helped build upon my foundational understanding of the language. A heavily syntactical exam which improved my writing but also gave me greater insight into the inner workings and main functional ideas behind the languages application to problem solving.

Misc:

Management of a git repository. Experience with Gitbash, Github and Gitlab.